In this video, I'm gonna talk about three different types of machine learning:
在这个视频中 我会介绍机器学习的三种类别
supervised learning, reinforcement learning and unsupervised learning.
监督学习 强化学习和无监督学习
Broadly speaking, the first half of the course will be about supervised learning.
大体而言 课程前半部分将会讨论监督学习
The second half of the course will be mainly about unsupervised learning, and
后一半主要讨论非监督学习
reinforcement learning will not be covered in the course, because we can't cover
这门课将不会涉及强化学习 因为我们不可能面面俱到
everything. Learning can be divided into three broad
机器学习可以被粗略地分为三类
groups of algorithms. In supervised learning, you're trying to
在监督学习中 你试图依据给定的输入向量来预测输出结果
predict an output when given an input vector, so it's very clear what the point
因此监督学习的特点很明显
of supervised learning is. In reinforcement level, you're trying to
强化学习中 你试图
select actions or sequences of actions to maximize the rewards you get, and the
选择一系列行为或行为序列来使得获得奖励最大化
rewards may only occur occasionally. In unsupervised learning you're trying to
而且这个奖励可能不定时产生的 在无监督学习中 你试图
discover a good internal representation of the input and we'll come later to what
找到对于输入数据的好的内在表达 我们将在后面对此详细解释
that might mean. Supervised learning itself comes in two
监督学习又可以被分为两类 回归和分类
different flavors. In regression, the target output is a real
回归问题中 目标输出是一个实数或者一个实数向量
number or a whole vector of real numbers, such as the price of a stock in six months
比如六个月以后的股价 或者明天中午的气温
time, or the temperature at noon tomorrow. And the aim is to get as close as you can
总之回归问题的目标是 让输出 尽可能地接近正确的实数或实数向量
to the correct real number. In classification, the target output is a
分类问题中 目标输出是一个分类标签
class label. The simplest case is a choice between one
最简单的例子就是在零和一之间二选一
and zero. Between positive and negative cases.
也就是在阳性和阴性之间给出一个选择
But obviously, we can have multiple alternative labels as when we're
当然 我们也可以有多个备选分类 比如手写数字识别问题
classifying handwritten digits. Supervised learning works by initially
在监督学习中 我们必须在一开始找到一个模型集合
selecting a model class, that is, a whole set of models that we're prepared to
里边是一系列的备选模型
consider as candidates. You can think of a model class as a
你也可以认为它是一个函数
function that takes an input vector and some parameters and gives you an output y.
根据输入向量 x 和相关的参数 W  能够得到相应的输出 y
So a model class is simply a way of mapping.
所以模型集合可以被认为是一种映射
An input to an output using some numerical parameters W and then we adjust these
从输入到输出的映射，使用了数值参数W，
numerical parameters to make the mapping fit the supervised training data.
我们对参数进行调整，使这种映射关系能拟合 相应的训练数据。
What we mean by fit is minimizing the discrepancy between the target output on
拟合，在这里指最小化每一条训练数据的目标输出和
each training case and the actual output produced by a machine learning system.
机器学习算法实际输出的差异。
And an obvious measure of that discrepancy, if we're using real values as
回归问题中，差异的度量，
outputs, is the square difference between the output from our system y, and the
常使用的是我们系统的输出y和正确输出t的差异的平方 再乘以二分之一
correct output t, and we put in that one-half, so it cancels the two when we
这个系数（二分之一）可以在求导的时候被消掉。
differentiate. For classification you could use that
对分类问题，
measure, but there's other more sensiblbe measures which we'll come to later, and
我们也可以使用这个度量， 但是存在更加敏感的度量方式，
these more sensibile measures typically work better as well.
其更有效，我们课程后面会详细描述。
In reinforcement learning, the outputs an actual sequence of actions, and you have
强化学习，输出是一系列动作
to decide on those actions based on occasional rewards.
你需要根据不定时的奖励来决定应该如何选择。
The goal in selecting each action is to maximize the expected sum of the future
所以目标是选择每个动作，使得将来的奖励最大化。
rewards, and we typically use a discount factor so that you don't have to look too
一般我们会使用一个衰减因子， 这样我们就不用计算到太远的将来。
far in the future. We say that rewards far in the future
换言之，很久以后才获得的奖励
don't count for as much as rewards that you get fairly quickly.
计算时的权重要低于马上就要获得的奖励
Reinforcement learning is difficult. It's difficult because the rewards are
强化学习很难，这是因为一般而言奖励是滞后的
typically delayed, so it's hard to know exactly which action was the wrong one in
所以很难确定一系列动作到底那个是错误的。
a long sequence of actions. It's also difficult because a scalar
强化学习很难，因为奖励是数值，
award, especially one that only occurs occasionally, does not supply much
是不定时给出的标量，起没有没有提供很多信息
information, on which to base the changes in parameters.
用以构建相应的参数。
So typically, you can't learn millions of parameters using reinforcement learning.
一般而言，强化学习中你没法学习出上百万的参数，
Whereas supervised learning and unsupervised learning, you can.
但是在监督学习和非监督学习中，是可以的。
Typically, in reinforcement learning, you're trying to learn dozens of
典型的强化学习，你试图学习
parameters or maybe 1,000 parameters, but not millions.
数十个或者一千个参数，但是不会是一百万个。
In this course, we can't cover everything, and so we're not going to cover
这个课程不会覆盖一切，
reinforcement learning, even though it's an important topic.
所以虽然强化学习很重要，但是我们不会涉及。
Unsupervised learning, is going to be covered in the second half of the course.
课程后半部分我们会讨论非监督学习。
For about 40 years, the machine learning community basically ignored unsupervised
长达40年的时间里 机器学习学界 基本上忽视了非监督学习
learning except for one very limited form called clustering.
除了聚类问题这一种非常有限的形式
In fact, they used definitions of machine learning that excluded it.
实际上 他们对机器学习的定义 就排除了非监督学习
So they defined machine learning, in some textbooks, as mapping from inputs to
在某些教科书上， 机器学习被定义为一种从输入到输出的映射
outputs. And many researchers thought that
很多机器学习研究人员认为
clustering was the only form of unsupervised learning.
聚类是唯一的一种非监督学习
One reason for this is that it's hard to say what the aim of unsupervised learning
原因之一是因为很难定义非监督学习的目的
is. One major aim is to get an internal
其中一个主要目的
representation of the input, that is useful for subsequent supervised or
是得到输入数据的内在表达，从而在接下来的
reinforcement learning. And the reason we might want to do that in
监督学习或者强化学习中排上用场。
two stages, is we don't want to use, for example, the payoffs from reinforcement
分成两个阶段，以强化学习为例， 是因为我们不想使用奖励来
learning, in order to set the parameters, for our visual system.
得到我们视觉系统的参数。
So you can compute the distance to a surface by using the disparity between the
你可以通过计算双眼看到的图像的差异来计算
images you get in your two eyes. But you don't want to learn to do that
到某个表面距离。 你肯定不会通过
computation of distance by repeatedly stubbing your toe and adjusting the
不停的调整你自己视觉系统的相关参数，
parameters in your visual system every time you stub your toe.
从而计算出相应的距离。
That would involve stubbing your toe a very large number of times and there's
真这样做， 会挪很多次，
much better ways to learn to fuse two images based purely on the information in
通过学习融合输入的两张图片提供的信息 无疑是更好的方式。
the inputs. Other goals for unsupervised learning are
非监督学习的另一个目标
to provide compact, low dimensional representations of the input.
是为输入数据提供一个紧凑，低维的表达。
So, high-dimensional inputs like images, typically, live on or near a
高维数据，比如图片， 往往存在或者近似与
low-dimensional manifold. Or several such manifolds in the case of
一个低维流形。 或者多个这样的流形，比如手写数字这个例子。
the handwritten digits. What that means is, even if you have a
具体的说， 你有一张一百万像素的图片，
million pixels, there aren't really a million degrees of freedom in what can
但是并不存在一百万维的自由度。
happen. There may only be a few hundred degrees of
可能仅仅只有几百个维度的自由度。
freedom in what can happen. So what we want to do is move from a
所以我们要做的是
million pixels to a representation of those few hundred degrees of freedom which
从百万像素
will be according to saying where we are on a manifold.
依据我们在流形相关信息，
Also we need to know which manifold we're on.
我们还需要知道我们在那个流形上。
A very limited form of this is principle commands analysis which is linear.
一个很基础的方式就是主成分分析，其是线性的。
It assumes that there's one manifold, and the manifold is a plane in the high
其假设存在一个流形， 其是高维空间的一个平面。
dimensional space. Another definition of unsupervised
非监督学习的另一个定义，
learning, or another goal for unsupervised learning, is to prov-, to provide an
或者另一个目标，
economical representation for the input in terms of learned features.
就是把输入转换为的表达。
If, for example, we can represent the input in terms of binary features, that's
比如，我们可以将输入表达为binary特征，
typically economical cuz then it takes only one bit to say the state of a binary
这样很经济， 因为每个变量只需要一个比特来说明其状态。
feature. Alternatively we could use a large number
或者我们可以是用大量的实数变量，
of real valued features but insist that for each input almost all of those
但是限制输入，使得几乎所有的变量都是0。
features are exactly zero. In that case for each input we only need
这种情况下，对每个输入，
to represent a few real numbers and that's economical.
我们仅仅要表达少数实数，这也是经济划算的。
As I mentioned before, another definition of unsupervised learning or another goal
前面提到过 非监督学习的另一个定义
of unsupervised learning is to find clusters in the input, and clustering
或者说它的另一个目标 是对输入进行聚类
could be viewed as a very sparse code, that is we have one feature per cluster
聚类也可以被认为是非常稀疏的编码， 对于每一个聚类我们有一个变量，
and we insist that all the features except one are zero and that one feature has a
那么对于所有变量来说， 除了一个，其他取值都为0，这一个取值为1。
value of one. So clustering is really just an extreme
所以聚类是稀疏编码的
case of finding sparse features.
一种极端形式。